Amir Nazemian

San Diego, California

- ■Phone: 202-246-3154 ■Email: anazemi1@gmail.com ■Homepage: www.amirforyou.com
- ■LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/anazemian ■GitHub: www.github.com/anazemian ■Twitter: www.twitter.com/amir_nazemian

SUMMARY

Currently mastering skills in Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS and ready for employment as a full-time junior web developer. Also acquiring experience in JQuery and Rails frameworks, APIs, and SQL. Resourceful, bilingual professional with additional experience in management, operations, sales, and customer service.

EDUCATION

LEARN Academy - San Diego, CA ~ May 2016

Full-Stack Development

University of Maryland - College Park, MD ~ May 2010

Bachelor of Arts, English Literature

Montgomery College - Rockville, MD ~ May 2007

Associate of Arts

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Ruby on Rails
- SQL
- Postgres
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- HTML and CSS
- TDD and BDD testing

EXPERIENCE

Market and Operations Manager, Zipcar, Inc. - San Diego, CA ~ October 2013 - January 2016

- Analyzed P&L and cost of goods sold to identify market opportunities
- Developed and implemented marketing strategies to increase market size
- Successfully closed numerous B2B opportunities and expanded B2B sales by 20% in 2015
- Cultivated working relationship with the City of San Diego
- Increased market size by over 50% in San Diego
- Reduced vendor costs by over 60% in San Diego

Operations Analyst, Wayfair LLC - Boston, MA ~ June 2011 - July 2013

- Identified opportunities at different points in supply chain and communicated findings to business partners to reduce cost of shipping goods
- Spearheaded a new model for an in-house freight carrier to shorten lead and shipping times
- Worked directly with suppliers, manufacturers, and carriers to reduce cost of damaged goods by 20%
- Maintained 90+ client accounts at all times
- Performed daily P&L analysis

Sales Associate, Wayfair LLC - Boston, MA ~ September 2010 - June 2011

- Exceeded monthly baseline for sales quotas by 43%
- Researched and contacted new prospects to generate additional revenue
- Identified trends and historical sales volume to build B2B forecasts and develop new sales
- Promoted from email staff to phone consultant within three months of start date

GROUPS

- Co-founder and Co-organizer of San Diego Surfing Devs
- SD Ruby
- San Diego.JS
- SD Reef Aquariums